Finding Aid for William Muschenheim papers 1923-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Digitization Project
  - 2002-2004, undated, 3 folders; 6 boxes; 2 boxes (Box 12)
70. James Kaplan, 630 Ninth Avenue, N.Y.C. New House, Rumson, N.J. 1940
71. New York World's Fair (1940), Flushing, L.I. Exhibit of a Modern Room, "America at Home" 1940
72. Robert D. Howard, Hotel Astor, Times Square, N.Y.C. House Alteration, Rumson, N.J. 1940
73. Seymour N. Fox, New Canaan, Conn. (Auto back-draft Protector) 1940
74. Wallace Lans, 286 Fifth Avenue, N.Y.C. (Wallpaper Design) 1940
75. F.A. Muschenheim, 218 West 45th Street, N.Y.C. Famses Development, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1941
76. Rudolph Serkin House Alteration, Great Neck, L.I. 1940
77. Hoyt & Page, National Press Bldg, Washington D.C. Aviation Building (Abandoned), Washington D.C. 1941
78. Museum of Modern Art, 11 West 53rd Street, N.Y.C. (Furniture Competition) 1941
79. William Hard, Jr., Chappaqua, N.Y. New House, Chappaqua, N.Y. 1941
80. Wm. J. Murphy, 44 East 67th Street, N.Y.C. Apartment Alteration, 44 East 67th Street, N.Y.C. 1942
81. Mrs. Samuel Garber, Hampton Bays, L.I. Bathhouses, Hampton Bays, L.I. 1941
82. George Nabolsine, 430 East 86th Street, N.Y.C. House Alterations, Bridgehampton, L.I. 1943
83. Dr. A. W. Hawkes, 285 Riverside Drive, N.Y.C. New House, Nassau Point, L.I. 1941
84. Alfred Wallenstein, Holmdel, N.J. Apartment Alteration, 40 Central Park South, N.Y.C. 1941
85. Russel Wright, 4 East 39th Street, N.Y.C. Proposed New House & Furniture Designs (?) 1941
86. Robert Shell Barn, Maine 1941
87. Common Sense New York, N.Y., 10 East 49th Street 1941
88. Technical Research Laboratories, Inc. Alteration, 535-41 East 79th Street, N.Y.C. 1942
89. Mrs. Louis M. Rousselot, 1235 Park Avenue, N.Y.C. Child's Room (shelves) 1944
90. Mr. W. Everit Burnet, 95 Gregory Avenue Alt. to House, West Orange, N.J. 1948
91. Mr. Seymour Prince, 158 Beach 145th St., Neponsit, N.Y. House at 154 Beach 145th St., Neponsit, N.Y. 1946
92. Mr. Wm. B.F. Drew, 570 Park Avenue, N.Y. 21, N.Y. Alteration to House, Westhampton Beach, N.Y. 1946
93. Lighthouse Alt., Hampton Bays, N.Y. 1946
94. Thomas A. Morgan, 217 East 62nd Street, N.Y.C. Alteration to House 1947
95. Eduardo Andrade, 215 East 72nd Street, N.Y.C. Alteration to Apartment 1946
96. Stiesel Medicinal Soap Co., Preston Hollow, N.Y. Soap Design "Cherbel" 1946
97. Edgar V. Bythiner, 230 W. 13th St. Apartment Alteration, 119 Payson Ave., N.Y.C. 1946
98.
99. Trinity Oper. Co., 74 Trinity Pl. N.Y.C. Alteration, 74 Trinity Pl. N.Y.C. 1947
100. Miss Bertha Mayers, Loveland, Colo. Cottage, Loveland, Colo. 1947
101. Prof. Martin Bernstein, 302 W. 12th St., N.Y.C. Screens, Etc., 302 W. 12th St., N.Y.C. 1948-49
102. The Soloman R. Guggenheim Fndtn., 120 Broadway, N.Y. 5, N.Y. Alt. to Museum, 1071 5th Avenue, N.Y.C. 1947-48
103. Irving Diamond, 1133 Broadway, N.Y.C. Alt. to Summer House, Hampton Bays, L.I. N.Y. 1948
104. William K. Schmidt, 601 West 160th St., N.Y. Alt. to Summer House, Hampton Bays, L.I., N.Y. 1948
105. Channing K. Jacques, 125 East 72nd St., N.Y. Alt. to Summer Residence, Hampton Bays, L.I., N.Y. 1947
106. Methodist Church, Hampton Bays, L.I.?, N.Y. Alt. to Church, Hampton Bays, L.I., N.Y. 1947
107. Fred A. Muschenheim, Hotel Astor, N.Y. Re-assembly of Bath Houses, Hampton Bays, L.I., N.Y. 1948
108. Robert G. Stewart, 320 Park Avenue, N.Y. Re: Alteration to House, East Hampton, L.I., N.Y. 1948
109. The Haitian Art Center, 937 Third Avenue, N.Y. Re: Alteration to Julius, Carlebach Galleries 1949
110. Prof. Martin Bernstein, 302 West 12th St., N.Y. Re: Guest Cottage, Amenia, New York 1948
111. Miss Terry Mason, 74 East 56th Street, N.Y. Re: Alteration to Apartment, 74 East 56th St., N.Y. 1948
112. Anita Zahn, 949 Park Avenue, N.Y. Alt. & addition to Summer, School of the Arts, East Hampton, L.I., N.Y. 1948
113. Wm. J. Murphy, Remsenburg, L.I., N.Y. Alt. & addition to Summer, Residence:Remsenburg, L.I. 1947-49
114. Mrs. H. Burnett, 156 East 79th St., N.Y. Alteration to Apartment, 156 East 79th St., N.Y. 1949
115. City and Country School, New York, N.Y. Alteration to School, New York, N.Y. 1949
116. Dr. W.A. Cooper, 1215 5th Avenue, N.Y. Alteration to Residence, Conn. 1949
117. Joseph Aronson, 118 East 37th St., N.Y. Alteration to Residence, 118 East 37th St., N.Y 1949
118. Paul Immo Gulden, 155 East 49th St., N.Y Alteration to Apartment, 155 East 49th St., N.Y. 1949
119. Dr. Carl Muschenheim, 215 East 72nd St., N.Y. Alteration to Apartment, 215 East 72nd St., N.Y. 1949
120. Wm. J. Murphy, 993 Fifth Avenue, N.Y. Alteration to Apartment, 993 Fifth Avenue, N.Y. 1949
121. Saul Friedman, Washington, Conn. Alteration to Residence, Washington, Conn. 1949
122. Joseph T. McGrath, Massapequa, L.I. Side Board for Residence, Massapequa, L.I. 1949
123. F.A. Muschenheim, Hotel Astor, N.Y.C. Gazebo Alt. to Res., Hampton Bays, L.I. 1950
124. Edward B. Brown, Berbrown Realty Corp., 200 Claremont Ave., N.Y.C. Alt. to Apt. House, 250 W. 20th St., N.Y.C. 1950
125. Dr. Carl Muschenheim, 133 East 64th St., N.Y.C. Alt. to Doctor's Offices, East 66th St., N.Y.C. 1950
126. Alfred Raustein, 1 Isley Pl., Malverne, N.Y. Alt. to Residence, Malverne, N.Y. 1950
127. F.A. Muschenheim, Hotel Astor, N.Y. Bay Ave. Development, Hampton Bays, N.Y. 1950
128. Dr. Virginia Lubkin, 128 East 71st St., N.Y.C. Alt. to Doctor's Office, 41 park Avenue, N.Y.C. 1951
129. William Muschenheim, 1941 Geddes Ave., Ann Arbor Alt. to res., 1941 Geddes Avenue, A.A. 1951
130. Salant, Edward O., 516 East 87th St., N.Y.C. Ramsenburg, L.I., Alt. to Res. 1951
132. Wm. Muschenheim, 1941 Geddes Avenue, Ann Arbor House, 1251 Heatherway, Ann Arbor 1952-53
133. Burton Harrison, 2633 Heatherway, Ann Arbor Alt. to Res. & Additions, 2633 Heatherway, Ann Arbor 1955-84
134. Prof. Martin Bernstein, 1 Blackstone Pl., N.Y. 71 Alt. to Res., 1 Blackstone Pl, N.Y.C. 1955
135. Rutledge, Don H., 1024 Westaire Way, A.A. House, 4075 N. Delhi Rd., Mich. 1957
136. Museum of Art, University of Michigan Main Stair, Platforms and Exhibition Space 1957
137. G. Bruce McCaleb, Farmington, Mich. Alt. to Residence, 33712 Glenview Dr. 1957
138. Ankara International Comp., Middle East Technical University Bldg. for School of Administrative Sciences 1960
139. FDR Hemprial Comp. Memorial in Washington 1961
140. Joseph Blatt, 1205 E. Stadium Blvd., A.A. Alt. to Res., 1205 E. Stadium Blvd., A.A. 1961
141. Harry Lieberman, Detroit, Mich. Designs for Development Houses 1960
142. Rackham Grant, University of Michigan, A.A. Elements of Architecture Plates 1961-64
143. A. Benj. Handler, 1028 Martin Place, A.A. Alt. to Res., 1028 Martin Place, A.A. 1961
144. A.I.A.
145. Robert E. Schwartz, 407 Jerome St., Midland, Mich. Consultations - Church, Shopping Center, Etc 1963
146. Phi Epsilon Pi Fraternity House, 1805 Washtenaw Avenue, Ann Arbor, Mich. Alt. and Annex (not completed), 1805 Washtenaw Ave., A.A. 1966
147. Claude A. Eggertsen, 1044 Ferdon Rd., Ann Arbor, Mich. Addition to Res. 1966
148. Rackham Grant 1964 Sabbatical Trip 1966
149. Richard Stoll Consultation re; Res
150. Alpha Ki Delta Sorority, Ann Arbor, Mich. Consultations re; Bldg. 1957
151. N.C.A.R.B., Washington, D.C. Foreign Evaluation Committee 1967
152. Sleepy Hollow Cemetery, Tarrytown, N.Y. Grave Stone, Lisa M. 1967
153. Emile Voelcker, Chapel Hill, N.C. Addition to Res. 1967
154.. ......
155. Muschenheim, Hammarskjold, Arms 201 East Liberty, Ann Arbor Office Alt. 1967
156. Dr. Eli V. Berger, Dr. Arnold I. Winshall, Detroit, Mich. Office Alt.
157. Mr. and Mrs. Ned Flanders, Heatherway, Ann Arbor Alt. to Res. 1968
158. Dr. C. Merle Dixon Alt to Office
159. Mr. and Mrs. Wray Hanck Alt. to Res.
160. Blue Cross/Blue Shield, 356 E. Congress St., Detroit, Mi. Remodeling of office Bldg.
161. 440 E. Congress St., Detroit, Mi. Remodeling of Parking Garage
162. International Organization Headquarters & Conference Center, Vienna, Austria International Competition 1969
163. Mr. and Mrs. Robert Knauss, Ann Arbor, Mich. Week-end House, Whitmore Lake, Mich. 1970
164. Dr. Frank Harary, Ann Arbor, Mich. Bldg. @ 3rd & Huron
165. Mr. and Mrs. Gerold Meyerson Alt. to Res.
166. Mr. and Mrs. Kalman, Birmingham, Mich. Alt. to Res.
167. Federation of Detroit Teachers, Detroit, Mich. Alt. to Headquarters
168. Mr. and Mrs. G.M. Berman, Huntington Woods, Mich. Alt. to Res.
169. Mr. Sabaliunas, Ypsilanti Michigan Alt. to Res. 1969
170. Mr. Lyne, East Lansing, Mich. Alt to Res.
171. R. Arms, Washington, D.C. Housing Project
172. Mr. Jos. T.A. Lee, Ann Arbor, Mich. Market Arbor "A" Center 1970
173. Dr. Gilbert M. Berman, 22100 Coolidge Rd., Oak Park, Mi. Alt. to Office
174. Mr. G.M. Berman, Huntington Woods, Mich. Color & Furniture for Res.
175. Correspondence re; Book
176. Rockresorts, 30 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y.C. Lobby -- Board Rm. 1971
177. Mr. Channing Jaques, Hampton Bays, L.I., N.Y. Addition to Cottage 1971
178. Mr. A.B. Handler, 2114 Devonshire, A.A. Addition to House 1972
179. Ann Arbor Trust Rental agreement 1972
180. Ann Arbor Bank 1972 Retirement Furlough 1972
181. City of Grand Rapids Museum re; Alt. to Old Federal Bldg. 1974
183. Dr. Helen Gay, 2650 Heatherway, Ann Arbor Addition to House 1976
182. W.M. House, 1251 Heatherway, Ann Arbor Improvements to S. Wing 1975
184. Mr. Ara G. Paul, 1415 Brooklyn, Ann Arbor Addition & Alt. to House 1977
185. Karoma Publishers, 3400 Daleview Dr., A.A. Bk. "Why Architecture" 1980
186. Mr. Hermann Hermannsson, 14376 Weber Rd., Saline, Mi. New House 1980
187. Mr. Silas Woods, 670 N. Harris, Saline, Mi. New House 1982
188. Mr. J.E. Keith Smith, 116 Heatherway, A.A. Railing at Approach to Res. 1983
189. Mr. Peter Meister, 2154 Spruceway, A.A. Alt. to Res. 1985